# Rubén D. Pire

# Full-Stack Developer

rpiredev@outlook.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

# **Summary**

I am a full-stack developer with a knack for understanding complex technical requirements and crafting elegant software solutions that empower users. I am a team player with an optimistic personality that can boost the morale of any team. My expertise lies in JavaScript and Ruby frameworks and technologies.

#### Skills

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Redux, Sass, Next

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, TypeScript, Mobile/Responsive Development, Design Systems

**Professional:** Remote Work, Pair-Programming, Teamwork

# **Experience**

<u>PALEOLIFE</u> Remote

### **Full-Stack Developer**

September 2024 – Present

 Decreased the online store's loading times by 25% by implementing best practices and performance upgrades.

 Decreased landing page's development time by 50% with the implementation of new customized Shopify sections to the online store.x

FREELANCING Remote

#### **Full-Stack Developer**

April 2023 – September 2024

- Built websites and web applications for clients worldwide following industry standards and best practices.
- Completed projects with tight deadlines working both collaboratively and independently.

MICROVERSE Remote

#### **Level Up Coordinator**

March 2022 - April 2023

- Mentored students, providing technical support, code reviews, and professional ethics.
- Facilitated the assimilation of the course's contents by proposing improvements to the lessons and space.

## Education

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

July 2021 – February 2022

- Accumulated 1300+ hours developing projects independently and collaboratively while simultaneously mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development.
- Honed communication skills by pair-programming, using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and following Scrum methodology with a remote team of international developers.
- Won the "Collaborator of the Month" award for my excellent performance while working on group projects.

### **UNEXPO**

**MICROVERSE** 

November 2011 – December 2018

### **Engineering, Electricity**

- Completed programming logic and algorithms coursework.
- Completed coursework about PLC programming.
- Worked as a university trainer for the Electrical Power Systems I subject, providing complimentary classes, assistance, and project reviews for senior-year undergraduates.